My friends and welcome to exercise, no aid to do in this exercise, we are asked to write a method
to test if a tree is a full binary tree or not.
So in order to save time and I am going to use that class binary tree that we have created in their
previous videos.
OK, so what I have done here is creating a class note that contains the item and contains the reference
to the left and the right pointer to the left and the right.
And I have created the constructor range analyzing the key equal to item equal to the past key when
we have creating a new node left equal to the right equal to not.
And I have created an object called the road from this node, and they have created the constructor
of this binary tree.
And these are the post order, pre order and in order traversal methods, OK that we have seen in the
tree traversal less and in the main, I have created this tree.
I will change the later on.
But till now, I'm interested in making this method that the checks here checking this exercise number
82.
By the way, you can get all of these source codes from the Resources folder in our Udemy courses below.
OK, now check.
Oops!
Check.
For full, finally, three.
We start by Mick.
This is public, Boolean goes through a return, is it true or false?
Is full binary tree and we pass the note here to the object.
No, please concentrate with me, guys.
I have to make this check in the previous video and see it's the same type.
It's the same context.
We start by checking the first step check, check.
If three is empty,
then if no equal, equal to null, then we return true.
OK, now check the children, check to check their children.
If note the left equal to none and no to the right, to equal, equal to none, then return through
again.
So we are checking if the notes to the left and the notes to the right equal to now than they are then
it is a full binary tree.
OK.
It contains more than one element.
The third step here, checking, all, checking on the sub threes if.
We have two Boolean expressions here.
Note the left does not equal to none.
If we have siblings and.
Nodes.
No, the tribe does not equal to none.
That this is very important if we have siblings, subgroups left and right are not equal to none.
So we have we have notes and we have data then return.
We need to use the recursive.
So we need to call it again is full binary tree.
Note to their left and it is full binary tree.
Note that height.
If they are equal, then return the.
If they are not known, this is the left and is right, if this expression is through and if this expression
is true, true and the true, it will return true.
Otherwise it worked.
If there is any of them is false, it will return.
False.
OK.
One of them returning false.
It will return false.
So I need to compare this to Boolean expression together.
True and the true, it will return true.
Otherwise, it will return false because either we have a left node equal to none or it is not fully
binary tree to the left or full binary tree to the right, then it will return false.
OK, if these conditions are not maintained, if these trees that you were situation are not maintained,
then return false in all the cases.
OK, so we are going to check of the node equal equal to null, then return true.
If the node equal left and the node the right equal to null, then return true.
And here we check if this sub tree to the left is binary tree.
And if all binary tree and the substrate to the right is sub three and is fully binary tree, then it
will return true.
Otherwise, it will return false.
OK, now let's test our program and let's see if it is a full binary tree or not.
Let's go to the main here and I will comment first.
OK.
I will create a new binary tree here Binary Tree three equal to new binary tree, and we start by creating
the first Node three dock node.
Equal to new node.
Sorry.
3.2 equal to new node.
And we passed number one.
Three Dot Root the left be equal to a new node to.
Three, through the.
I will post the video and paste the code in order to save the time I have created this binary two three
one two three, four, five, six and seven.
And by the way, I am creating and testing this binary three one, two, three, four, five and six
and seven.
This is a full binary tree and this is what we have created in the previous video and see and I am going
to repeat it and Java in order to test it.
So let me close this.
Yes.
And the let's check here, if Brent, if three dot is full binary tree and we three through it, then
we put in system system that out sprint and this three, that tree is a full binary tree.
OK.
Else it will look for me, a system that the brain.
This tree is not a full binary.
OK.
Now, let's run this program and see.
And here we go.
This tree is a full binary tree, and it's very correct because we are testing.
We have inserted this nodes according to a full binary tree figure.
So we have learned about the binary as a full binary tree and how to create it in C and in.